# Summary

Ph.D. economist and engineer, fluent in Chinese Mandarin, French and English.

Specialized in advanced econometrics and statistical models applied to financial and monetary issues.

IMF missions to more than 20 countries, including as mission chief, leading teams of four people on IMF technical assistance missions with central banks worldwide.

My Github page and Github repo contain open-source statistical packages on forecasting and financial modeling. For more information, please visit: https://romainlafarguette.github.io/

# Professional Experience

# International Monetary Fund, Economist

Monetary and Capital Markets, Central Bank Operations Division	Since 2019
European Department, Southern Europe Desk (EP)	2018-19
Monetary and Capital Markets, Financial Stability Analysis Division (EP)	2016-18
European Central Bank, Economist and Portfolio Manager	
Macroprudential Policy & Financial Stability, Financial Regulations Division	2015-16
Market Operations, FX Reserves Trading Desk	2014-15
International Directorate, International Policy Analysis Division	2013-14

#### Education

Ph.D. in Economics, Peking University (CCER) & Paris School of Economics	2017
Six years in China, Ph.D. curriculum entirely done in Chinese Mandarin	
M.A. in Philosophy, Paris Sorbonne University	2009
Major in Epistemology and Philosophy of Medicine	
M.Eng. in Applied Mathematics, ENSAE Paris	2009
Major in Statistics	
M.Res., Normalien, Ecole Normale Superieure de Paris Saclay	2007
Ranked first at France's national entrance competition	
Undergrad in Mathematics and Philosophy, CPGE Henri IV Paris	2005
Military High-School, Prytanee National Militaire de La Fleche	2003

#### Macrofinancial Feedback, Bank Stress Testing and Capital Surcharges (2020)

with T. Adrian (IMF) and J. Berrospide (US Federal Reserve Board)

### Foreign Exchange Interventions Rules for Central Banks: A Risk-Based Framework (2020)

IMF Working Paper No. 21/32, with R. Veyrune (IMF)

#### Predictive Density for Global Growth (2020)

IMF Working Paper No. 20/78, with F. Caselli, F. Grigoli and C. Wang (all IMF)

#### Growth at Risk: Concept and Application in IMF Country Surveillance (2019)

IMF Working Paper No. 19/36

#### Can Countries Manage Their Financial Conditions Amid Globalization? (2018)

IMF Working Paper No. 18/15, with N. Arregui, S. Elekdag, G. Gelos and D. Seneviratne (all IMF)

#### Trading Without a View: Fast Trading, Entropy and Underreaction in the FX Market (2018)

With G. Corsetti (Cambridge) and A. Mehl (ECB)

#### Thick vs. Thin-Skinned: Technology, News, and Financial Market Reaction (2016)

IMF Working Paper, with B. Eichengreen (Uni. Berkeley) and A. Mehl (ECB)

# Cables, Sharks and Servers: Technology and the Geography of the Foreign Exchange Market (2016)

NBER Working Paper No. 17/91, with B. Eichengreen (Uni. Berkeley) and A. Mehl (ECB)

Invoicing Currency, International Trade and Redenomination Risk (2015)

# Understanding Household Savings in China: The Role of the Housing Market and Borrowing Constraints (2014)

With M. Bussiere, Y. Kalantzis (both Banque de France) and T. Sicular (Uni. Western Ontario)

# **Policy Publications**

## House Price Synchronization: What Role for Financial Factors? (2018)

Global Financial Stability Report, International Monetary Fund, April 2018, Chapter 3

#### Financial Conditions and Growth at Risk (2017)

Global Financial Stability Report, International Monetary Fund, October 2017, Chapter 3

### Are Countries Losing Control of Domestic Financial Conditions? (2017)

Global Financial Stability Report, International Monetary Fund, April 2017, Chapter 3

# High-Frequency Trading, Information and Market Volatility: the Role of High-Frequency Quoting and Dark Pools (2016)

Macroprudential Bulletin, European Central Bank, October 2016, Chapter 3

#### The Role of Currency Invoicing for the Transmission of Exchange Rate Movements (2015)

The International Role of the Euro, European Central Bank, July 2015, Special Feature (with J. Grab)

# Software Development

More details and links to the programs: https://romainlafarguette.github.io/software/

Distributional GaRCH model to design VaR-based FX Interventions for Central Banks https://github.com/romainlafarguette/varfxi

#### Quantile local projections

https://github.com/romainlafarguette/quantileproj

Density Forecasting Using Growth At Risk: Python Codes and Excel Interface

https://github.com/IMFGAR/GaR. With technical appendix and documentation

# Teaching

#### Forecasting with Quantile Regressions (2020)

Course for the South East Asian Central Banks (SEACEN) Research and Training Centre, July 2020

#### Clinic on Growth-At-Risk and Density Forecasting at the IMF

Course for the IMF Institute of Capacity and Development, April 2019

## Introduction to Python for IMF economists

IMF, European Department, April 2019

#### Linear and Non-Linear Econometrics, Statistics, Macroeconomics

ENSAE and Sciences Po Paris, 2010-2012

#### Skills

Languages
Programming
Quant

Fluent in Chinese Mandarin, fluent in English, French native speaker

Python, R, Matlab, STATA, SQL, VBA

Quant Parametric and non-parametric inference, forecasting, machine learning, big data